One will trust in the power of prayer. One will
believe in the might of the sword.
The Mission is a adventure, drama, action film directed by Roland Joffé.
When a Spanish Jesuit goes into the South American wilderness to build a mission in the hope of
converting the Indians of the region, a slave hunter is converted and joins his mission.
When Spain sells the colony to Portugal, they are forced to defend
all they have built against the Portuguese aggressors.
Rodrigo Mendoza, played by Robert De Niro.
Father Gabriel, played by Jeremy Irons.
Cardinal Altamirano, played by Ray McAnally.
Felipe Mendoza, played by Aidan Quinn.
Father John Fielding, played by Liam Neeson.
Carlotta, played by Cherie Lunghi.
The Mission is a 1986 British historical drama film directed by
Roland Joffé, from a screenplay by Robert Bolt.
It stars Robert De Niro and Jeremy Irons, with Ray McAnally, Aidan
Quinn, Cherie Lunghi and Liam Neeson in supporting roles.
It is about the experiences of a Jesuit
missionary in 18th-century South America.
The film is partly based on Paraguayan saint Roque
González y de Santa Cruz and the Guaraní War.
The film premiered in competition at the 39th Cannes
Film Festival, winning the Palme d'Or.
At the 59th Academy Awards, it was nominated for seven awards including Best
Picture and Best Director, winning for Best Cinematography.
The film has also been cited as one of the greatest religious films of all time, appearing in the Vatican film
list's "Religion" section and being number one on the Church Times's Top 50 Religious Films list.
The film explores themes of mission, resistance,
christianity, religious conversion, based on true story.
The tone is emotional.